<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scientific articles on Maria Soto Lima</title>
    <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scientific articles on Maria Soto Lima</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 12:49:27 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Operation Research</title>
      <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/about-or/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/about-or/</guid>
      <description>Qu’est-ce que c’est la Recherche Opérationnelle (RO) ?  La RO est la mise en application de méthodes mathématiques et algorithmiques afin de trouver la meilleure façon de procéder ou le meilleur choix en prenant en compte le contexte et les enjeux dans le but d’attendre le meilleur résultat possible.
La RO a été largement appliqués dans l’optimisation des processus de la chaîne logistiques, du bon fonctionnement de grands réseaux de télécommunication, de production d’énergie, l&amp;rsquo;ordonnancement, la gestion de stock, l&amp;rsquo;affectation de moyens à des tâches, les problèmes d&amp;rsquo;investissement en finances entre autres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most important publications</title>
      <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/best_publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/best_publications/</guid>
      <description>List of my best scientific publications
 International journals  M. Soto, A. Rossi, M. Sevaux, A Multiple Neighborhood Search for dynamic memory allocation in embedded systems, Journal of Heuristics, pp 1-31, 2015. doi:10.1007/s10732-015-9297-y. M. Sevaux, A. Rossi, M. Soto, A. Duarte, R. Martí, GRASP with Ejection Chains for the dynamic memory allocation in embedded systems, Soft Computing, 18 (1), pp 34-42, August 2014. doi:10.1007/s00500-013-1157-9. M. Soto, A. Rossi, M. Sevaux, Iterative approaches for a dynamic memory allocation problem in embedded systems, European Journal of Operational Research, 231 (1), pp 34-42, November 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Conferences</title>
      <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/international_conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 13:06:26 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/international_conference/</guid>
      <description>List of international conferences
 International Conferences  M. Sevaux, M. Soto, A. Rossi, A. Reinholz, Multiple neighborhood search for the multi-depot open vehicle routing problem. Network Optimization Workshop, La Rochelle, France. 10-20 Mai 2015. M. Sevaux, A. Reinholz, M. Soto, A. Rossi, OVRP for the transportation of handicapped people. Proceedings of the LOT conference - A special EU/MEeting in memory of late Professor Arne Løkketangen, Molde, Norvège. Septembre 2014, pp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Conferences</title>
      <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/french_conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/french_conferences/</guid>
      <description>List of french conferences
 French Conferences  M. Soto, M. Sevaux, and A. Rossi. Optimisation du transport de personnes handicapées, ROADEF 2014, Bordeaux, France, 26-28 February 2014. M. Soto, M. Afsar, F. Hnaien, H. Snoussi, Problème de surveillance par capteurs mobiles, ROADEF 2013, Troyes, France, 13-15 February 2013. M. Soto, A. Rossi, M. Sevaux, J. Laurent, Approches itératives pour l&amp;rsquo;allocation de mémoire dynamique dans les systèmes embarqués, ROADEF 2012, pp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book</title>
      <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/book/</guid>
      <description>Book  M. Soto, M. Sevaux, A. Rossi, J. Laurent, Memory Allocation Problems in Embedded Systems. Optimization Methods. ISTE/Wiley, 2013. Available here.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis</title>
      <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/thesis/</guid>
      <description>My Phd Thesis and my graduate thesis
 PhD Thesis  M. Soto, Optimization methods for the memory allocation problems in embedded systems, UBS, France, Septembre 2011. Thesis advisors: Marc Sevaux and André Rossi. My PhD thesis defense slides is available for download.  Graduate Thesis  M. Soto, Algoritmos de optimización para un problema estocástico de flujo de caja, Ecuador, 2007. Thesis advisor : Luis Miguel Torres.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecuadorian Jounal</title>
      <link>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/ecuadorian-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariasoto.github.io/blog/ecuadorian-journal/</guid>
      <description>Ecuadorian Journal  M. Soto, L.M. Torres, Modelo estocástico y algoritmos en-línea para el problema de gestión de saldo en caja en el Banco Central del Ecuador (Stochastic optimization model and online algorithms for the management of account balance in the Central Bank of Ecuador), Cuestiones Económicas, vol. 23, N. 1, first quarter 2007. pp. 99-124.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
